technology is risky but when we create
technology together when we own it
together we greatly reduce the risk and
we spread it out there's just less risk
when we do it together so part of the
risk in any new app that I covered in
the last video is that there aren't
enough people to make the app itself
viable probably because partly cause of
marketing for Italy cuz of a funding
model and just maybe there aren't enough
people who would meets a need for once
we have a threshold of people who share
a problem childcare they like to eat
they you know air travel whatever it
happens to be that there is not
something out there meeting the needs of
there's a reason that they have a real
complaint with the for-profit model in
it you get enough of those people
together to co-create a solution a
technology solution that works for them
as individuals and they Co fund it they
all put money in in order to say yes we
want this to be be a solution want to be
able to hire someone to make it once
we've done that we already have a pool
of people in the more universal the
first problems we solve are like food we
all need to eat the bohr we have a base
of people to make even the news projects
so we have to solve it once and yes
there'll be what the word is people
leave people will leave probably but as
long as we're giving them something to
remain we're making whatever a
contribution they're making more than
worthwhile and we're creating a
community that is fun to be a part of
easy to contribute to we're going to
have more people joining them leaving
we're gonna want their friends and
family to come on board and the more we
create it so it's Omni win so the more
people that come on board and bring
their data and bring their ideas and
bring their mental emotional physical
labor the better it is for all of us
then we're going to want more people on
board so the people problem is like a
one-time problem we need enough people
to start the first project
then we need those people to be invested
enough not financially not risking not
taking a big risk so that they feel like
their life is on the line or their
finances their retirement their health
is gonna be on the line because I'm able
to feed their family in a decade we're
solving problems we're saying hey this
might not help you feed your family the
game a capitalist system there's a
reason it's it's it's you take on risk
to get big rewards
it's very very risky we can make sure
everybody's fed everybody has health
care everybody has education by making
that a priority and getting people
together who don't have health care and
have them create a solution getting
people together who don't have a
nutritious food and helping them create
a solution and so we we together fix the
people problem because we want more
people on board
you're not coming on board and being
duped this isn't an MLM or the like
further down you come in the worse it is
for you this is like yes come bring your
ingenuity bring your data bring who you
are with you we spread out the financial
risk including listening to people who
are like I can't afford that right now
if we want you on board and we want you
on board we need to listen to that and
find ways that work for people who can't
afford $10 a month if that's the fever
we're at at that moment and how do we
get you to the point where you can
afford $10 a month and you clearly can
see you can afford $10 a month if we get
you there you can give us $10 but we
also have longevity built into it
because we're looking for what we're
never gonna be perfect but we're owning
that we're not perfect we're transparent
help us make it better help the next
iteration be better why are you leaving
truly can we help you stay can we help
you keep your data here why would you go
to the other one because $10 month and I
can't afford it lost my job okay you can
stay well more crying
there are so many ways life is risky
right now we've created the tools to
truly connect and solve problems within
for each other with losing your job
doesn't mean you have to worry about
your family because you know there's a
backup system that goes way beyond any
kind of safety net the government will
create we have real power then so not
only are we creating technology without
the risk in a space that's very risky
we're reducing the risk for every
individual member in their lives to be
part of a system that they know they can
have a direct impact on their own lives
by helping co-create solutions to
problems that directly affect them like
hey I lost my job and now I don't know
where how I'm gonna feed my family your
options are the food bank your options
these things even getting access to that
information to know where they are and
what you need to do is powerful then
creating our own safety net our own
solutions that aren't the food bank that
are like hey you want to go work on a
farm they'll give you food why not be
perfect keep telling us what's not
perfect about it how do we keep making
it better and so there's less risk
involved when we're in it together and
we do it together every new person
brings less risk with them every hour
every day every year we're in business
we are going to create something so
powerful that we have less risk as a
company and we have less risk as
individuals a better world is on its way
please like and subscribe